Kassoy, Hortense Slides and Photographs 6386 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Hortense Kassoy Slides and Photographs
1970-2007
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kassoy, Hortense
6386 P
1.67 cubic feet
1.7 linear ft.
Photographs, 35mm slides.
8507662
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 18, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 23, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Hortense (Honey) Kassoy, who died at 96 on July 5, 2013, was an artist as adept with a chisel as she was with a paint brush.
Honey, as she was known to all, moved with her husband Bernard (Bernie) to the Amalgamate Houses in 1950 and they quickly became active members of the community.
Among the many activities Honey as she was known to all embraced were the Amalgamated Nursery School, the co-op's visual arts committee, the costume ball committee, a publication called Co-op Voices and the Apricot theater group. Her sculpture, "Maternal Force," is a permanent fixture in the courtyard of the two Amalgamated towers located on Sedgwick Avenue between Saxon and Dickenson avenues.
She was a teacher at Evander Childs High School and a founding member of the Bronx Council on the Arts who was instrumental in founding the Bronx Museum of the Arts.
Honey was corresponding secretary for the United Stats Committee of the International Association of Artists, a branch of UNESCO, from 1979 to 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
8507662
- Sculpture negatives - removed from a three-ring binder labeled "Sculpture" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- H. Kassoy Slides: Batiks (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sculpture slides (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  contents from a three-ring binder
- Sculptures -- 1986-2004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Slides -- The Making of Woman (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Sculpture slides -- 1970-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sculpture slides -- 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Slides & Photos -- 85th Birthday Exhibition -- 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Pilobolus at Tallix -- negative strips (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Honey's work (Box 1, Folder 10)
  slides and negatives
- Elderhostel - Alfred U. (May 22-June 1, 1994; Merry June 1994) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- TALLIX - negs only & index sheet (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Working at TALLIX (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photocopy of a photo of Honey (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Graduation pictures of former students (Box 2, Folder 4)
  contents of a photo wallet
- Photos of Bernie and Honey (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Exhibit - Contact sheets, negatives, photos (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Strip sheet + Negs; Tango Arg + Slow Rhumba; Apt + the Queen (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Negs; Proof Sheet - Honey (Pasde Deaux) Sculpture -- B-Misc. landscape, etc. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Arch Odette Winter dance Dark Ritual (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 80th Birthday Exhibition - negs (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Strip Sheets + Negs - PTE (B), Sculpt (H) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Strip Sheets + Negs -- September Song - Mar. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ariel B Prints - Fallen Hero - Negs + Proof Sheets (Box 2, Folder 13)